Radwan Ahmed

Front-End Engineer

radwananik.ra@gmail.com (+88)01873843384 radwananik.netlify.app/ linkedin.com/in/radwananik/

Front End Engineer almost 4 years of experience with React JS, Next JS, HTML/CSS to deliver impact web solution. Collaborating effectively with designers, developers, and stakeholders to achieve project goals. Skilled in optimizing performance, accessibility, and usability to provide the best user experience.

WORK EXPERIENCE

QCOOM - Front-End Engineer

January 2023 - Present

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Work collaboratively with designers, back-end developers, and stakeholders to develop and maintain responsive web applications for the company's e-commerce platform.
- Utilize React, Next, Tailwind and other framework to implement new features and improve the performance of existing code.
- Write clean, maintainable, and testable code using best practices and established coding standards.
- Collaborate with the QA team to ensure proper testing and debugging of applications.
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility and responsive design of websites.

Tiger IT Bangladesh Ltd - Front-End Engineer

May 2019 – January 2023

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Worked with design, product, and back-end teams to create 5+ web & cross platform products.
- Increase Performance, Accessibility, and SEO from 70% to 95% as per lighthouse.
- Develop an admin system for maintain 300+ employee details information using HTML,CSS,JS
- Consuming and integrating restful API in a JS application and optimized application for maximum speed.
- Design a cross-platform app using Ionic, React, and SCSS for daily task assign.

SKILLS

- HTML5 and CSS3
- JavaScript
- React.js
- Next.js
- Ionic
- JQuery
- Bootstrap
- Scss
- TailwindCss
- Antd
- · Responsive Design

- Accessibility Standards
- Mobile-first Development Practices
- Cross Browser Compatibility
- Web Performance Optimization
- Git
- Jira
- Redmine
- Figma
- Adobe Xd
- Agile
- Familiarity: Rest API | Typescript | Cypress | Redux | Java | Jsp | WordPress | SEO

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSE

- Certificate on JavaScript Programming | <u>Stydysection</u>
- JQuery UI Widget | <u>Udemy</u>
- Rapid Usability Research for UX | <u>Udemy</u>
- Foundation Software Testing | <u>Linkedin Learning</u>
- Understand Manual Testing | <u>Linkedin Learning</u>

EDUCATION

Daffodil International University - Bachelor of Science, Computer Science & Engineering

January 2015 - December 2018

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Higher Secondary School – Ibn Taimiya School & College, Science

2012 - 2014Cumilla, Bangladesh

PROJECT

- Qcoom: Front-End Tech Next JS | Scss | Antd Remote(Demo) Responsibility: UI Develop, Modifying UI, Responsive Design, Data Fetching
- QFood-Store: Front-End Tech Next JS | TailwindCss Remote(Demo) Responsibility: UI Develop, Responsive, SEO, Data Fetching
- Bangladesh Voter Registration System: Front-End Tech JavaScript | JQuery | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap -TigerIT

Responsibility: UI Develop, Maintain and improve website

- HR Management: Front-End Tech JavaScript | JQuery | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap -TigerIT (Demo) Responsibility: UI Develop, UI Design, Optimize application
- Task-Management: Front-End Tech React | Ionic | Scss TigerIT (Demo) Responsibility: UI Develop, Data Fetching
- **QFood-landing:** Front End Tech-React | Scss | Antd Remote(Demo) Responsibility: UI Develop, SEO, Data Fetching
- QFood-Admin: Front End Tech-React | Scss | Antd Remote(Demo) Responsibility: UI Develop, Data Fetching, SEO
- Forum: Front-End Tech JavaScript | JQuery | Scss | Bootstrap -Template (Demo) Responsibility: UI Develop, SEO, Data Fetching
- Piickme: Front-End Tech React | Scss | Antd -Remote (Demo) Responsibility: UI Develop, SEO, Data Fetching

Reference

Mustofa Rizwan Assistant Vice President (Lead) TigerIT Bangladesh Limited

Email: tumancse03@gmail.com

Tasnur Rahman Tonov **Project Manger Bkash Limited**

Email: trtasnur@gmail.com